Guide to the George Washington University Publications collection, 1924-2017 RG0154
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University Publications collection
1920-2017
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
RG0154
55 Linear Feet 38 records cartons, 15 manuscript boxes
This is an artificial collection composed of printed materials acquired by Special Collections Reearch Center at various times. The collection was created in 2019 from original MARC records. The collection printed materials and paper documents published by the George Washington University. The publications date generally from 1924-2017.
Biographical / Historical
This is an artificial collection composed of printed materials acquired by Special Collections Research Center at various times. The collection was created in 2019 from original MARC records.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of publication, portions of publicatons and other printed materials. These materials were originally individually cataloged and managed in the library's ILS. The primary subject of the materials relates to the schools and departments of the University. The items date from approximately 1924-2017.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
The publications are grouped by which department or school created the publication. Otherwise, they are grouped by topic.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The publications acquired over many years from different sources.
- Engineering, Series 1
  - Technology and the Modern University: A report by the President's Advisory Committee on Engineering and Applied Science, November 1966; Series 1; [4], 58 pages: graphs; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Contains the results of a study by the Committee on the future of the University's School of Engineering and Applied Science.; Cover title.; Includes bibliographical references (page 22).
  - School of Engineering and Applied Science, 1982-10-01; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs Vol. 1, 1977-06-01; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs Vol. 2 Pt. 1, 1977-06-01; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs Vol. 2 Pt. 2, 1977-06-01; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs Vol. 2 Pt. 3, 1977-06-01; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Occupational Structure in the Military and Civilian Sectors of the Economy, 1974-09-25; Series 1; iv, 22 leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    "This report was prepared under the Navy Manpower R &amp D Program of the Office of Naval Research under Contract Number N00014-67-A-0214, Task 0016, Project NR 347-024."; Issued as Serial TR-1224.; Work performed as part of the program in Econometric Research on Navy Manpower Problems.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 21-22).
  - On the Treatment of Uncertainty in Parametric Costing, 1976-02-02; Series 1; 192 pages illustrations, charts, tables. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 179-192).; Thesis -- George Washington University.
  - Phase one report: evaluation of maritime protection practices and proposals on U.S. bulk trade by Robert C. Waters, C. Peter Schumaier., 1984-02-24; Series 1; 37, [60] leaves; 30 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    "24 February 1984."; Includes sections by David J. Sharpe and Alexander Tsolakis.; Includes bibliographical references.; Sponsored by Department of Transportation, contract DTRS-5683-C-00002.
  - On the predictive performance of the BEA quarterly econometric model and a Box-Jenkins type ARIMA model by Gorti V.L. Narasimham, Victor F. Castellino, Nozer D. Singpurwalla., 1974-09-20; Series 1; 20 leaves: graphs; 30 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Contract N00014-67-A-0214, Task 0001, Project NR 347 020, Office of Naval Research.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 19-20).
  - Reexamination of the adaptive expectations hypothesis when applied to a cobweb model by Barry D. Nussbaum, Nozer D. Singpurwalla., 1977-05-31; Series 1; 9 leaves; 30 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    "Contract N00014-75-C-0729, Project NR 347 020, Office of Naval Research."; Includes bibliographical references (leaf 9).
  - The stochastic formulation of a modified cobweb model by Barry D. Nussbaum [and] Nozer D. Singpurwalla., 1977-05-16; Series 1; 20 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Includes bibliographical references (leaves 19-20).
  - Computing equilibria via nonconvex programming by Jonathan F. Bard, James E. Falk., 1978-11-10; Series 1; 36 leaves: illustrations; 30 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Research sponsored by U.S. Army Research Office under contract DAAG29-76-G-0150.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 33-36).
  - Methodology of the LEAP model by James E. Falk, Garth P. McCormick, Richard M. Soland., 1979-03-30; Series 1; vi leaves, 120 pages: illustrations; 30 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Research supported by Contract 451887-S, Brookhaven National Laboratories.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 119-120).
  - Risk-benefit analysis for industrial and social needs, by Kendall D. Moll and Dennis P. Tihansky., 1976-06-17; Series 1; 27 lvs. illustrations, charts. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Includes bibliographical references (lvs. 26-27).
  - An overview of the shipbuilding labor market by Sheldon E. Haber, John C. Martin., 1976-03-24; Series 1; 10 pages; 30 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Contract N00014-75-C-0729.; Project NR 347 020.; Serial T-331.; Includes bibliographical references (page 10).
  - The labor market of the United States shipbuilding industry, 1960-1970 by John Charles Martin., 1978-06-30; Series 1; viii, 165 pages; 30 cm. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Contract N00014-75-C-0729.; Presented as the author's thesis, George Washington University.; Project NR 347 020, Office of Naval Research.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 159-165).
  - Jobs, occupations, careers by Charles T. Stewart, Jr., 1976-06-01; Series 1; iv, 17 leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 18)
    "Report ... prepared under the Navy Manpower R &amp D Program of the Office of Naval Research under Contract Number N00014-75-C-0610, Project NR 347-024."; Work performed as part of the program in Econometric Research on Navy Manpower Problems.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 16-17).
  - Manpower policy and the reenlistment rate by Sheldon E. Haber, T. Ireland, Herbert Solomon., 1974-06-10; Series 1; iv, 45 leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 19)
    "Report ... prepared under the Navy Manpower R &amp D Program of the Office of Naval Research under Contract Number N00014-67-A-0214, Task 0016, Project NR 347-024."; Issued as Technical Report, Serial TR-1201.; Work performed as part of the program in Econometric Research on Navy Manpower Problems.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 39-40).
  - Applications of a Wage-Turnover Model to the Shipbuilding Industry, 1980-02-08; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Adaptive forecasting of the size of a force subject to random withdrawals by S. Zacks., 1975-05-09; Series 1; 27 leaves; 30 cm. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    "Contract N00014-75-C-0729, Project NR 347 020, Office of Naval Research."; Includes bibliographical references (leaf 22).
  - The design of the thematic maps for computer display by Michael W. Dobson, John L. Sibert., 1982-02-01; Series 1; 63 leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 22)
    "February 1982."; "IIST Report 82-17."; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 60-63).; Research supported by U.S. Geological Survey, Department of the Interior, under contract 14-08-0001-20448.
  - Final report, fire-load research project: NBS grant #6-9003 submitted to National Bureau of Standards ... by the George Washington University, School of Engineering and Applied Science; prepared by John Pressley., 1977-01-10; Series 1; i, 21, [7] leaves; 30 cm (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Computer crime: science fiction and science fact by Kurt J. Schmucker., 1982-09-25; Series 1; 50 pages; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 24)
    "GWU-IIST-82-19."; "September 25, 1982."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 38-50).
  - Some Statistical Results for Inventory Models with State-Dependent Leadtimes, 1972-04-24; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- International Topics, Series 2
  - Achieving greatness by J. Willard Marriott, Jr., 1985-10-01; Series 2; 10 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    "October 1985."; Based on a commencement address delivered at George Washington University in 1982.
  - Industrial Relations Seminar: the George Washington University, Airlie House, October 25-28, 1970 by Master Printers of America, Printing Industries of America., Series 2; approximately 100 leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Cover title.
  - Current readings in personnel edited by Roy B. Eastin., Spring 1970; Series 2; approximately 150 leaves: illustrations; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Used in a personnel updating seminar held in the spring, 1970 at George Washington University.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Conference Proceedings of the Mid-Atlantic Regional Meeting of the Conference proceedings of the Mid-Atlantic Regional Meeting of the American Accounting Association: March 17-19, 1977., 1977-03-01; Series 2; v, 165 pages: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Conference held at the Cloyd Heck Marvin Center of George Washington University.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Proceeding of the Eastern Academy of Management, 1976-05-01; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting the problems of very small enterprises, by Janet M. Pomeranz [and] Leonard W. Prestwich. Prepared by the George Washington University under the Small Business Administration Management Research Grant Program. Project directors: A.M. Woodruff [and] J.C. Dockeray., 1962-12-01; Series 2; xii, 154, [53] pages diagrams, tables 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University mid-career executive development program presented by the College of General Studies in cooperation with the School of Government and Business Administration., Spring 1970; Series 2; approximately 400 pages: illustrations; 30 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Program presented at George Washington University in spring, 1970.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Steering nonprofits: advice for boards and staffs [written by the staff of the Management Assistance Group]., 1991; Series 2; 15 pages; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Caption title.; Originally printed in 1984 as a special issue of Conserve neighborhoods.
  - The expanding role of non-profit organizations as contractors with government: some research needs., 1968-03-01; Series 2; 19 pages 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Includes bibliographical references.
  - Guidelines for the improvement of wealth data and estimates; report of the wealth inventory planning study, the George Washington University. Edited by John W. Kendrick (staff director)., 1964-06-01; Series 2; 4 volumes illustrations 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    volume 1. Report by the staff.--v.2. Background papers.--v.3-4. Reports of the sector working groups.
  - Guidelines for the improvement of wealth data and estimates; report of the wealth inventory planning study, the George Washington University. Edited by John W. Kendrick (staff director)., 1964-06-01; Series 2; 4 volumes illustrations 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Guidelines for the improvement of wealth data and estimates; report of the wealth inventory planning study, the George Washington University. Edited by John W. Kendrick (staff director)., 1964-06-01; Series 2; 4 volumes illustrations 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Guidelines for the improvement of wealth data and estimates; report of the wealth inventory planning study, the George Washington University. Edited by John W. Kendrick (staff director)., 1964-06-01; Series 2; 4 volumes illustrations 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The multinational corporation: a review of some problems and opportunities for business management in a period of world-wide economic change., 1960; Series 2; 32 pages (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Psychological types and organization strategy by Warren J. Keegan., 1977-11-01; Series 2; 59, iv leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    "Working Paper #77-."; Research supported by a grant from the General Electric Foundation.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves iii-iv).
  - Vesting, private pensions, social security, and family savings by James R. Barth, Joseph J. Cordes, Robert B. Friedland., 1982; Series 2; 34, [2] pages; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Research in part supported by the George Washington University facilitating fund.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 35-36).
  - The challenge of business leadership in the 1980's by Irving Kristol., 1985-10-01; Series 2; 9 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    "October 1985."; Based on a commencement address delivered at George Washington University in 1980.
  - The relative efficiency of private and public transfers by Joseph J. Cordes, Robert S. Goldfarb, Harry S. Watson., 1983-05-01; Series 2; 20, [4] leaves: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    "May 1983."; Research in part supported by the George Washington University facilitating fund.; Includes bibliographical references (leaf 22).
  - Marketing planning strategies for contraceptive social marketing (CSM) programs in developing countries by Adel El-Ansary and Cheryl Gardner., 1985-08-01; Series 2; 53 leaves: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    "August 1985."; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 49-53).
  - Business and government: partnership for the future by Lee A. Iacocca., 1985-10-01; Series 2; 11 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    "October 1985."; Based on commencement address given at George Washington University, May, 1979.
  - Managerial effectiveness in Singapore and Indonesia: a neo-classical extension of the Farmer-Richman model by Herbert J. Davis, Lau Wah Ming, Thomas F. Brosnan., 1985-11-01; Series 2; 28 leaves: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Includes bibliographical references (leaves 24-28).
  - Foreign investment in the People's Republic of China: a study of investment incentives and environment in the Shenzhen Special Economic Zone by Phillip D. Grub and Jian-hai-lin., 1985-09-01; Series 2; 49 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    "September 1985."; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Trends in private investment in developing countries 1993: statistics for 1970-91 by Guy P. Pfeffermann, Andrea Madarassy., Series 2; v, 63 pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Investments under uncertainty and irreversibility: rational indecision and a numerical investigation of the 2-D free boundary problem by Spiros H. Martzoukos., 1995; Series 2; 67, 2 pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    "July 1995."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 62-67).
  - Future trends in managerial beliefs: a comparative study by Salah S. Hassan, Tarek A. Hatem., 1995-10-01; Series 2; 24 pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    "October 1995."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 18-19).
  - European logistics alliances: a management model by Prabir K. Bagchi and Helge Virum., 1995-11-01; Series 2; 27 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    "November, 1995."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 22-23).
  - Role of benchmarking as a competitive strategy by Prabir K. Bagchi., 1995-11-01; Series 2; 22 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    "November, 1995."; Includes bibliographical references (page 18).
  - Catalog mix adaptation to international markets: an empirical study by Fernando Robles and Syed Akhter. to International Markets: An Empirical Study, 1995-11-01; Series 2; 43 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    "November 1995."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 34-35).
  - Home sweet home: cooperative interorganizational relations and domestic strategies in the advertising industry by Douglas M. Sanford, Jr.: Cooperative Interorganizational Relations and Domestic Strategies in the Advertising Industry, 1995-11-01; Series 2; 27 pages; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    "November, 1995."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 21-24).
  - Middle East crude oil pricing and risk management in the 1990s by Robert J. Weiner., 1995-12-01; Series 2; 47 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    "December, 1995."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 34-35).
  - The importance of convexity vs. bond theta: you may be surprised by Don M. Chance and James V. Jordan., 1995-12-01; Series 2; 14, [7] pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    "December, 1995."; Includes bibliographical references (page 14).
  - Surveys of marketing research directors in Fortune 500 firms, 1965-1975-1985-1995 by James R. Krum and Pradeep A. Rau., 1995-12-01; Series 2; 8 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "December 1995."
  - Management of newly privatized industries: a background paper by Mehmet Ozkaya and Hossein Askari., 1996-01-01; Series 2; 30 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    "January, 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 29-30).
  - Firm-theoretic limitations on Proposition III by Paul S. Peyser., 1996-02-01; Series 2; 46 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    "February 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 37-39).
  - The informational contents of currency options and futures by George M. Jabbour., 1996-03-01; Series 2; 15 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    "March 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 12-13).
  - Transactional uncertainty and plural forms of governance by Joseph P. Cannon, Ravi S. Achrol, Gregory T. Gundlach., 1996-04-01; Series 2; 28, [10] pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    "April 1996."; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Forms of network organization by Ravi S. Achrol., 1996-04-01; Series 2; 41, [5] pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    "April 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 36-41).
  - The profitability of small traders in futures markets: a review of research by James V. Jordan and David I. Meiselman., 1996-05-01; Series 2; 50 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    "May 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 48-50).
  - Capital flows and financial stability: the Mexican experience by Jiawen Yang., 1996-05-01; Series 2; 17, [3] pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    "May 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 16-17).
  - Scope and impact of innovations in emerging Islamic financial markets by Zamir Iqbal., 1996-06-01; Series 2; 33 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    "June 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 28-33).
  - Contrarian MacParity by Reid W. Click., 1996-08-01; Series 2; 5 leaves: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    "August 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (leaf 3).
  - Seigniorage in a cross-section of countries by Reid W. Click., 1996-10-01; Series 2; 30 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    "October 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 20-22).
  - Regional corporate strategies and regional market integration in the Americas by Fernando Robles and William D. Schulte., 1996-10-01; Series 2; 28 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    "October 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 26-28).
  - The behavior of holding period returns and risk for the major market indices 1973-1993 by Frederick Amling and Mark A. Peirce., 1996-10-01; Series 2; 17 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    "October 1996."
  - Crossborder acquisition strategies in Latin America in 1995-1996 by Fernando Robles., 1996-12-01; Series 2; 32, [11] pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    "December 1996."; Includes bibliographical references.
  - On rational redemption policy with transaction costs for bonds and securitized pools of bond-like instruments by Therodore Barnhill and Spiros Martzoukos., 1996-12-01; Series 2; 40 pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    "December 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 22-26).
  - Petroleum fiscal dependence: revenue forecasting and oil price volatility by Robert J. Weiner., 1996-12-01; Series 2; 58, [25] pages, [40] pages of plates: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    "December 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 56-58).
  - Multivaraite contingent claims with stochastic cost of exercise and multiplicative uncertainties by Spiros H. Martzoukos., 1996-12-01; Series 2; 17 pages; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    "December 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 15-17).
  - Expansion of the European Union to the east: issues and problems by G. Peter Lauter and Scheherezade S. Rehman., 1996-12-01; Series 2; 20 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    "December 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 19-20).
  - Impact of shocks to exchange rates and oil prices on U.S. sales of American and Japanese automakers by Brad M. Barber, Reid W. Click, Masako N. Darrough., 1996-12-01; Series 2; 41, [6] pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    "December 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 36-38).
  - Factors affecting the yield on noninvestment grade bond indices by William F. Maxwell, Theodore M. Barnhill, Jr. amd Fred Joutz., 1997-02-01; Series 2; 39 pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    "February 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 38-39).
  - Factors influencing user satisfaction with marketing decision support systems: a comparison of U.S. and Korean respondents by Jeong Wan Doo and Pradeep A. Rau., 1997-04-01; Series 2; 23 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    "April 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 20-23).
  - An introduction to credit derivatives and their potential use by domestic banks in emerging markets Liliana Schumacher., 1997-08-01; Series 2; 28 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    "August 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (page 28).
  - Opening (Initiating) and Closing (Offsetting) Option Volume and Opening (initiating) and closing (offsetting) option volume and informed trading around earnings dates by Arthur J. Wilson., 1997-08-01; Series 2; 38 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    "August 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 36-37).
  - Opening (Initiating) and Closing (Offsetting) Option Opening (initiating) and closing (offsetting) option volume around periods of abnormal stock returns by Arthur J. Wilson. Stock Returns, 1997-08-01; Series 2; 30, [7] pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    "August 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 21-23).
  - The determinants of bank interest rate margins: an international study by Anthony Saunders and Liliana Schumacher., 1997-09-01; Series 2; 30 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    "September 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 28-30).
  - Optimal long-horizon mean-variance portfolio strategies by Isabelle Bajeux-Besnainou and James V. Jordan., 1997-10-01; Series 2; 28, [4] pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    "September 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 17-19).
  - Macroeconomic policy credibility and its determinants by Hossein Askari and Mohamed Jaber., 1997-10-01; Series 2; 13 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    "October 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (page 13).
  - Hysteresis models of investment with multiplicative uncertainties by Spiros H. Martzoukos., 1997-11-01; Series 2; 21 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    "November 1997."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 18-21).
  - Standardization drivers, levers, and performance: a conceptual framework and some preliminary findings by A.N.M. Waheeduzzaman and Pradeep A. Rau., 1998-01-01; Series 2; 32 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 36)